Rodolfo Portillo III

626 W Lullwood Ave, San Antonio, Texas 78212

(915) 240-4687

rplf65@gmail.com

https://www.rportillo.com

Quality Assurance Software Tester with experience in several areas of product support which include manual software testing, test case creation, defect triage, and reporting of tests executed and defects uncovered. This experience is supplemented with in-depth, day-to-day customer support of bespoke government content management system.

Areas of experience include:

JIRA/Confluence	 Design, develop and execute automation scripts using open- source tools 	 Web app testing including mobile responsivness
 Create detailed, comprehensive, and well- structured test plans and test cases 	 Develop and apply testing processes for new and existing products to meet client needs 	 Experience creating automation frameworks written in C# and Selenium
 Locating UI elements and comparing expected test results against actual application behavior on multiple browser platforms 	 Perform thorough regression testing when bugs are resolved 	 Experience with testing for multiple projects in an Agile development envirnment

Certifications

Security+ CE

CompTIA, June 2019 Expires: June 2022

A+ CE

CompTIA, June 2021 Expires: June 2024

Network+ CE

CompTIA, September 2021 Expires: September 2024

ITIL V4 Foundation

AXELOS, September 2020

Expires: N/A

Secret Security Clearance

Department of Defense, September 2020

Expires: N/A

Work Experience

QA Engineer, ManTech Intl. (Formerly Gryphon Technologies); San Antonio, Texas

November 2020 – Present

- Full web app testing including UI validation
- Mobile responsiveness testing of sites across browsers and operating systems with BrowserStack
- Draft and catalog test cases using Xray software inside Jira
- Write custom QA automation test cases in C# and Selenium
- Utilize GitHub for codebase versioning maintenance
- Test and automate using sprints in an Agile CI/CD pipeline deployed with Jenkins
- Build and implement APIs using Postman
- Primary QA Engineer for the Department of Defense homepage defense.gov

Service Desk Analyst, ManTech Intl. (Formerly Gryphon Technologies); San Antonio, Texas

May 2019 – November 2022 (1 Year, 6 Months)

- Provide support for basic incident resolution and requests reported to the Service desk.
- Assist customers through phone calls, emails and ticket tracking system.
- Resolve issues by completing initial assessment, triage, research, and resolution of basic incidents and requests regarding the use of application software products and infrastructure components.

Line Cook, Alamo Drafthouse Cinemas; Austin, Texas

February 2017 – May 2019 (2 Years, 3 Months)

- Responsible for the training of new hires in various areas of a professional kitchen
- Follow corporate recipes for food preparation with a major focus on accuracy and minimal
- Responsible for maintaining consistent execution of entrees in a fast-paced, high-pressure environment
- Adhere to all state health compliance requirements

Field Tech II, Texas Gas Service; Austin, Texas

November 2013 – December 2016 (3 Years, 1 Month)

- Part of a team responsible for maintaining the integrity of the natural gas infrastructure for Austin. TX
- Held and maintained several government-required qualifications pertaining to natural gas
- Developed strong teamwork and dynamic problem-solving skills in a hazardous environmen

Education

Western Governors University (WGU Texas); Austin, Texas

July 2020 - Present

Major: B.S. Information Security and Assurance

GPA: 3.5

Anticipated Graduation: January 2023

Austin Community College; Austin Texas

December 2016 - May 2019

Major: A.S. Information Security and Assurance

GPA: 2.75

University of Texas at El Paso; El Paso, Texas

August 2008 – May 2012

Major: B.S. Computer Science

GPA: 2.5